A Guide to the Sarah S. Driggs Papers, 1986-1993
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Sarah S. Driggs Papers, 1986-1993
The Library of Virginia
38814
1.8 cu. ft. (4 boxes)
Driggs, Sarah S.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donor information unavailable.
Biographical Information
Sarah Shields Driggs was a researcher with the Historic Richmond Foundation and the Library of Virginia. She gathered illustrations and research for the book, Virginia's Executive Mansion, by William Seale.
Scope and Content
This collection includes research materials gathered by Sarah Driggs for the book, Virginia's Executive Mansion, written by William Seale. Sarah Driggs was a researcher who worked with the author, the Historic Richmond Foundation, and the Library of Virginia on the book. The files generally remain in the order kept by Sarah Driggs.
Includes correspondence between the author, photographer, and publications department of the Library of Virginia, notes on drafts of the book, copies of photographs used for the book and ones rejected, a National Register of Historic Places registration form for the mansion, a preliminary outline of the history of the mansion, and a draft of the book. Also includes copies of accounts, bills, correspondence, invoices, legislative acts, newspaper clippings, plans, receipts, and reports for materials purchased and improvements made to the governor's mansion. These files are arranged chronologically by decade, starting in 1810 to the 1990's. Also includes a paper written by Sarah Driggs, "Comfort, Convenience, and Elegance: A History of the Bolling Haxall House," 1992.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- Appendix (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Chapter 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Comfort, Convenience and Elegance: A History of the Bolling Haxall House," 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1988 January-May (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1988 June-August (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1988 September-December (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1989-1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Documentation, Exterior, 1810s (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Documentation, Interior, 1810s (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Documentation, Exterior, 1820s (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Documentation, Interior, 1820s (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Documentation, History, 1820s (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Documentation, Invoices, etc., 1820s (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Documentation, Exterior, 1830s (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Documentation, Interior, 1830s (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Documentation, History, 1830s (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Documentation, Exterior, 1840s (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Documentation, Interior, 1840s (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Documentation, History, 1840s (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Documentation, Exterior, 1850s (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Documentation, Interior, 1850s (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Documentation, Exterior, 1860s (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Documentation, Interior, 1860s (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Documentation, History, 1860s (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Documentation, 1870s (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Documentation, 1880s (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Documentation, History, 1890s (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Documentation, General, Early 20th century (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Documentation, Exterior, 1900-1910 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Documentation, Interior, 1900-1910 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Documentation, History, 1900-1910 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Documentation, Interior, 1910s (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Documentation, History, 1910s (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Documentation, History, 1920s (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Documentation, Pre-fire, 1920s (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Documentation, Post-fire, 1920s (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Documentation, Exterior, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Documentation, Interior, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Documentation, History, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Documentation, History, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Documentation, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Documentation, History, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Documentation, Mid-to-late 20th century and undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Drawings, prints, maybe (Box 3, Folder 1)
- General history (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Maps (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 4)
- National Register of Historic Places Registration form (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Notes from reviews (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Ordered (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Photographs, exterior, maybe (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Photographs, interior, maybe (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Photographs, Erik Kvalsvik (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Photographs, old, maybe (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Photographs, other houses, no (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Photographs, people, maybe (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Photographs, to be used (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Policies, documents, etc. (Box 3, Folder 16)
- "A Preliminary Outline of the History of the Governor's Mansion," (not to be reproduced) (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Research, need to order (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Research, rejected (Box 4, Folder 2)
- "Virginia's Executive Mansion," Master office copy, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Photograph of Governor's mansion, c. 1865 (Folder Oversize folder 1)